<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Curious on Polyglot</title>
    <link>https://bowmansolutions.com/polyglot/curious/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Curious on Polyglot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 21:48:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bowmansolutions.com/polyglot/curious/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust</title>
      <link>https://bowmansolutions.com/polyglot/curious/rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 21:48:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bowmansolutions.com/polyglot/curious/rust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://doc.rust-lang.org/stable/book/&#34;&gt;the Rust book&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust is a systems programming language focused on three goals: safety, speed, and concurrency. It maintains these goals without having a garbage collector, making it a useful language for a number of use cases other languages aren’t good at: embedding in other languages, programs with specific space and time requirements, and writing low-level code, like device drivers and operating systems. It improves on current languages targeting this space by having a number of compile-time safety checks that produce no runtime overhead, while eliminating all data races. Rust also aims to achieve ‘zero-cost abstractions’ even though some of these abstractions feel like those of a high-level language. Even then, Rust still allows precise control like a low-level language would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elm</title>
      <link>https://bowmansolutions.com/polyglot/curious/elm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 21:47:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bowmansolutions.com/polyglot/curious/elm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Elm aims to make web development more pleasant. Elm is a type inferred, functional reactive language that compiles to HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/elm-lang/elm-compiler&#34;&gt;the elm-compiler Github repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it a new functional language, a Javascript library, or somebody&amp;rsquo;s trendy computer science project? Worth investigating&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>